Edward Wilson believed in America, and he would
sacrifice everything he loved to protect it.
The Good Shepherd is a drama, thriller, history film directed by Robert De Niro.
Edward Wilson, the only witness to his father's suicide and member of the Skull and Bones Society while a student at Yale, is a morally
upright young man who values honor and discretion, qualities that help him to be recruited for a career in the newly founded OSS.
His dedication to his work does not come without a price though, leading
him to sacrifice his ideals and eventually his family.
Edward Bell Wilson, played by Matt Damon.
Margaret Ann Russell, played by Angelina Jolie.
Bill Sullivan, played by Robert De Niro.
Sam Murach, played by Alec Baldwin.
Philip Allen, played by William Hurt.
Joseph Palmi, played by Joe Pesci.
The Good Shepherd is a 2006 American spy film produced and directed by Robert De Niro, and starring
Matt Damon, Angelina Jolie and De Niro, supported by an extensive ensemble cast.
The film follows Edward Wilson, a fictional counterintelligence officer,
from 1939 to 1961 as the CIA develops and grows around him.
Wilson (played by Damon), a senior CIA officer, discovers a mole in his
department following the disastrous Bay of Pigs invasion of 1961.
The film delves into Wilson's complex life, starting from his college years at Yale in 1939, his initiation into
the Skull and Bones fraternity, and his recruitment into intelligence work (during World War II).
His personal life is marked by a strained marriage to Margaret "Clover" Russell (played by Jolie), and by a
series of affairs, that underscore the sacrifices, and moral compromises, invited by espionage work.
The narrative unfolds through a mix of sequential events and flashbacks, exploring the origins of the CIA, the Wilson character's
involvement in key historical events, and the personal tolls typical in careers dedicated to secret intelligence.
The film was released on December 22, 2006 by Universal Pictures in North America and by
Morgan Creek International in international markets, to mixed reviews.
It grossed $100 million against an estimated $80 million production budget.
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, london, england, central
intelligence agency (cia), husband wife relationship, cuba.
The tone is emotional and intense.